Now that we've compiled the model,
我们已经编译好模型
we're ready for training.
可以训练模型了
The training steps should look somewhat familiar from the last lesson.
训练步骤和上节课的差不多
To understand the modifications,
要了解修改的地方
we'll first need to introduce the idea of model validation.
我们首先需要知道模型验证这一概念
So far, we've checked how well our models are
到目前为止 我们都是根据损失和准确率
performing based on how the loss in accuracy changed with epoch.
随着 epoch 的变化而如何变化来判断模型效果
If you've designed your own models,
如果你自己设计了模型
you've likely discovered that it's not always clear how many layers
就可能会发现并非始终都清楚网络应该具有多少层级
the network should have or how many nodes to place in each layer.
或每层应该有多少个节点
How many epochs should you use?
应该使用多少个 epoch
There are a lot of decisions that need to be made when designing an architecture.
在设计架构时 需要作出很多决定
One method that's used in practice involves breaking
实际操作中用到的一种方法是
the data set into three sets called train,
将数据分成三个类别
validation and test sets.
分别是训练集 验证集和测试集
Each is treated separately by the model.
模型会单独处理每个数据集
The model looks only at the training data when deciding how to modify its weights.
模型在决定如何修改权重时 仅使用训练数据
At every epoch, the model checks how its
在每个 epoch 模型通过检查验证集的准确率
doing by checking its accuracy on the validation set.
来判断模型的效果
But its important to note that it does not use
但是务必要注意的是
any part of the validation set for the back propagation step.
模型不会使用任何验证集进行反向传播
We use the training set to find all the patterns we can and
我们使用训练集来查找所有的规律
the validation set tells us if our chosen model is performing well.
并用验证集来判断所选模型效果是否不错
Since the model doesn't use the validation set for deciding the weights,
因为模型不使用验证集来决定权重
it can also tell us if we're over-fitting to the training set.
它还可以告诉我们是否对训练集进行了过拟合
For instance, say use of the model to train for 200 epochs,
例如 假设用模型训练了 200 个 epoch
but around epoch 100,
但是在大约第 100 个 epoch 时
you notice some evidence of over-fitting,
你发现了一些过拟合现象
where the training loss starts to decrease but the validation loss starts to increase.
训练损失开始下降 但是验证损失开始增大
Then you'll want to keep the weights around epoch 100,
然后你希望保留大概在第 100 个 epoch 的权重
and ignore or throw away the weights from the later epochs.
并忽略或放弃后续 epoch 的权重
This is along the lines of what we do in the notebook.
我们在 notebook 中就是这么操作的
But this kind of process can also prove useful if
但是如果我们有多个潜在架构可供选择
we have multiple potential architectures to choose from.
这种流程也很有用
Say for instance, you're deciding the number of layers to put in the model.
例如 你要判断模型中应该有多少层
Then you'll want to save the weight from
那么你需要保存每个潜在架构的权重
each potential architecture for later comparison.
以便后续进行比较
And you'll always pick the model that gets the lowest validation loss.
你始终会选择验证损失最低的模型
You might be wondering, why must we create a third dataset?
你可能有疑问 为何必须创建第三个数据集
Couldn't we just use the test set for this purpose?
使用测试集不行吗？
Well, the idea is that when we go to test the model it
当我们测试模型时
looks at data that it has truly never seen before.
模型会查看完全从未见过的数据
Even though the model doesn't use the validation set to update its weights,
虽然模型不使用验证集来更新权重
our model selection process is biased in favor of the validation set.
但是模型选择流程也会偏向于验证集
Thus, we need three separate sets of data.
因此我们需要三组独立的数据集
Returning to the code,
回到代码部分
notice that the fit method takes validation split as an argument.
注意 fit 方法将 validation_split 作为参数
In this case, we've supplied 0.2.
在此处 我们将其设为 0.2
So 20% of the data originally assigned as
即有 20% 原先分配为训练数据的数据
training data will be removed from the training set and instead used as a validation set.
将从数据集中拿出来当做验证集
The model checkpoint class permits us to save the model weights after each epoch.
ModelCheckpoint 类允许我们在每个 epoch 之后保存模型权重
The file path parameters specifies the location where we'd like to save the weights.
filepath 参数指定了权重的保存位置
By setting the 'save best only' parameter to 'true',
通过将 save_best_only 参数设为 True
you can tell the model to save
可以告诉模型仅保存权重
only the weights to get the best accuracy on the validation set.
以让验证集达到最佳准确率
When you set verbose to one,
将 verbose 设为 1
the text output during the training process
训练过程中的文本输出将告诉你
will let you know when the weights file is updated.
权重文件何时更新了
After creating this check pointer,
创建此 checkpointer 后
you pass it as a parameter when you fit the model. But now it's your turn.
在拟合模型时将其传入为参数 现在该你来操作了
Run the model in the Jupyter notebook and take a look at the training output.
在 Jupyter notebook 中运行该模型 并查看训练输出
You should see that on most epochs,
应该看到对于大多数 epoch
the validation loss decreases.
验证损失都下降了
This is a sign that we've created
这表明我们创建了良好的模型
a good model and we'll get good performance on the test dataset.
我们将在测试数据集中获得好的效果
We'll check this out in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中看看效果如何